bottegaveneta.com 2018-02-23

# Bottega Veneta - Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy

Welcome to our website bottegaveneta.com (the “ **Site** ”). Please read our Privacy Policy carefully. 

This Privacy Policy applies when you visit or surf the Site without purchasing any product, when you register on the Site and when you use our services for purchasing products. By using this Site, you accept the practices described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not want to accept the practices described in this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Site.

Since personal data (“ **Personal Data** ”) of users and customers (collectively " **Users** ") of this Site may be processed in the European Union, notably in Italy, processing of Personal Data will be conducted in compliance with the Governing Law.

Your personal data is collected and processed by Bottega Veneta SA and the companies of Kering Group ("Kering Group") as well as by their service providers located within and outside of the European Union (collectively " **us** ", " **we** ", " **our** "). Bottega Veneta SA has its registered offices at Cadempino 6814, Switzerland, Via Industria 19 - CH-501.3.016.726-0 . For any issues relating to this Privacy Policy you can contact our [Customer Care](https://www.bottegaveneta.com/clientservice/contact-us/).

Your Personal Data will be processed to provide the services you subscribed to or reserved for registered users, to facilitate your navigation of and shopping from the website and to keep you informed of Kering Group news and offers.

Bottega Veneta SA and the companies of Kering Group are jointly controllers of Personal Data, within the meaning of Directive 95/46/EC of 24 October 1995 (herein, “ **Controllers** ”), collected and processed for purposes of rendering the e-commerce services and the sale of products (herein the “ **E-Commerce Purposes** ”) through the Site, together with YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP S.p.A. with registered offices in via Morimondo, 17 – Milano 20143, Italy, Milan Business Register, Tax and VAT number 02050461207, share capital Euro 1,338,942.89 fully paid up.

The management of the sale of the products and the transactions performed on bottegaveneta.com, within the United States of America are operated, under license, by YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP S.p.A.’ s subsidiary YNAP Corporation, a Delaware corporation having an address at 100 Fifth Avenue – 12th floor, New York, NY 10011, United States of America ("YNAP USA", YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP S.p.A. and YNAP USA also jointly referred to as YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP).

YNAP USA is the controller of personal data of users and customers of the Site within the United States of America, which is collected for conducting, concluding and performing transactions for purchasing products on the aforementioned site. As required by the Italian Data Protection Code, YOOX USA has appointed YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP S.p.A. as its data protection representative in Italy. As our data protection representative in Italy, YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP S.p.A. ensures that personal data are processed in Italy in a correct and lawful manner and in accordance with good practice. Since personal data of users and customers collected for conducting, concluding and performing purchase transactions through the Site in the United States of America may be processed in Italy, any such processing of personal data will be conducted in compliance with applicable US law as well as the Italian Data Protection Code (Legislative Decree no. 196 dated June 30, 2003).

Bottega Veneta SA and the companies of Kering Group are the sole Controllers of the Personal Data processed for marketing purposes, notably to send to Users, also through newsletter, information and updates on its products, offers, exclusive sales, promotional campaigns and on events and similar initiatives organized by Bottega Veneta SA (herein the “ **Marketing Purposes** ”), which we believe may be of interest to Users, as well as for purposes of creation and analysis of individual profiles.

**1\. Our Policy**  
Everyone has the right to protection of his/her Personal Data. We and YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP respect Users’ right to be informed regarding the collection of and other operations involving their Personal Data. In using data that may directly or indirectly identify you personally, we will apply a principle of strict necessity. For this reason, we and YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP have designed the Site in such a way that the use of your Personal Data will be kept to a minimum and will not exceed the purposes for which your Personal Data was collected and/or processed; we and YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP do not process your Personal Data when we can provide you with services through the use of anonymous data (such as marketing research made for improving our services, browsing data processed to provide you with customized contents or offers adapted to your preferred language, your location, etc.) or by other means which allow us and YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP to identify you, apart from when it is strictly necessary or upon request by competent public authorities or the police (for example, in case of traffic data or your IP address).

This Privacy Policy provides you with all information needed to understand how we and YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP collect Personal Data. For further information on our Privacy Policy, please contact us and/or YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP through our [Customer Care](https://www.bottegaveneta.com/clientservice/contact-us/), or Bottega Veneta SA and/or YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP at their registered offices indicated above.

As part of Kering Group, we and the companies of Kering Group comply with Kering Group’s Binding Corporate Rules on privacy and data protection. As our provider of e-commerce services, YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP complies with Kering Group’s Binding Corporate Rules. For further information on Kering Group’s Binding Corporate Rules, click here.

**2\. Who collects and processes Your Personal Data, how and for which purposes?**  
YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP, Bottega Veneta SA and the companies of Kering Group may be jointly or respectively the Controllers of your Personal Data as they determine the E-Commerce purposes and means of processing Personal Data. For the E-Commerce purposes only, YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP and Bottega Veneta SA have appointed certain entities that will also process Personal Data relating to the Site’s Users (herein the “ **Processors** ” or where mentioned individually “ **Processor** ”).

The above mentioned service providers and Processors have been chosen because of their experience in processing Personal Data and they provide sufficient safeguards regarding compliance with the Governing Law (including the technical security measures governing the processing to be carried out). In processing the Personal Data for E-Commerce Purposes, the Processors shall act only under the instructions from YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP or from Bottega Veneta SA. We regularly check that our Processors comply with our instructions and that they continue to provide sufficient guarantees regarding their full compliance with the provisions on Personal Data processing.

Some of the Processors of your Personal Data appointed by YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP for E-Commerce purposes directly are:

United Parcel Service, for purposes related to shipping, delivering and returning products purchased on bottegaveneta.com;

BT Italia S.p.A., for purposes related to the housing of YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP servers;

XCSE Abramo GmbH for call center services.

Bottega Veneta SA has appointed ContactLab S.r.l., with registered office at Via Natale Battaglia 12, 20127, Milan, Italy, as a data Processor for Marketing Purposes.

For the E-Commerce purposes, we and YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP collect your Personal Data (such as personal details, email address, address, credit card numbers, bank code, tax code and telephone number, etc.) on your order form only for the purpose of selling the products ordered by you. Your Personal Data is mostly processed by electronic means and, in some circumstances, by paper-based means, such as when the processing of your Personal Data is required for preventing fraud on the Site. Your Personal Data shall be stored in a way which allows us to identify you for the period necessary for the purposes which the data was collected for and subsequently processed and, in any case, in accordance with the Governing Law. Please report any modification of your Personal Data to our [Customer Care](https://www.bottegaveneta.com/clientservice/contact-us/) or through your personal account on the Site in order to ensure that your Personal Data is always accurate and up-to-date, relevant and complete. Your Personal Data shall not be disclosed to third parties for purposes which are not permitted by law or without your consent.

Aside from the Processors appointed for Personal Data processing, your Personal Data will also be made available to third parties, autonomous controllers, for purposes related to supplying services requested by Users (for example, for purchase transactions) or for purposes of third parties. For more information on the matter, see section 4 (To Whom Your Personal Data Will Be Disclosed). Please contact our [Customer Care](https://www.bottegaveneta.com/clientservice/contact-us/) if you would like to receive a full list of our Processors involved in processing your Personal Data.

For the Marketing Purposes, we may process your Personal Data as well as browsing data (“ **Traffic Data** ”) resulting from the use of our Services by any User, via both automated and non-automated means, including by phone, mail and email, in order to provide Users with customized contents and offers on our Services or to deliver any newsletter they subscribed to, subject to their discretionary right to withdraw their subscription to such newsletter or to oppose or object to the receiving of any advertising or marketing content which we think is of interest to a specific User. For Marketing Purposes, Personal Data and Traffic data is mostly processed by electronic means and shall be stored for us in any case, in accordance with the Governing Law and made available to our Processors.

Moreover, your Personal Data may be disclosed to the police or to judicial authorities, according to the Governing Law and upon a formal request by such entities, for example in the event we need to prevent fraud on the Site (anti-fraud services).

Processors will also have access to your Personal Data as stated in section 2 for the specific purposes stated therein. In all the above circumstances, your consent for data processing is not required as Personal Data Processing would be necessary for the performance of E-Commerce purposes.

The reasons for collecting Personal Data will be expressly listed in the information of privacy statement that we will present from time to time on the page asking the User to provide his or her Personal Data, be it for E-Commerce purposes or for Marketing Purposes. We and YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP may have access to third parties’ Personal Data which was directly disclosed by its Users, for example when a User bought a product to be sent to a friend, when the User paying for the product is different from the recipient of the product, or when a User wishes to recommend to a friend a service of the Site or the sale of a particular product. In all of the above cases, please make sure you receive the consent of such individuals before disclosing their Personal Data to us and make sure you inform them about this Privacy Policy; you will be the only person liable in connection with the disclosure of information and data regarding such third parties if they have not provided you with their prior explicit consent for it and for any improper and unlawful use of that information. In any event, we and YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP shall use reasonable efforts to inform third parties required by law and, when necessary, shall request their explicit consent upon registering in its archives the Personal Data of the User indicated.

**3\. What Happens if You Do Not Disclose Your Personal Data to us?**  
Granting your Personal Data to us and YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP (in particular, your personal details, your email address, your address, your credit/debit card numbers and bank code and your telephone number) is necessary for processing your order for the purchase of products on the Site, supplying other services provided on the Website upon your request, or when your Personal Data is needed to fulfill obligations required by law or regulations. The refusal to provide us and YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP with some of your Personal Data necessary for performing the above purposes may consequently prevent us or YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP from processing your order for the purchase of products sold on the Site or fulfilling obligations required by law and other regulations. Therefore, failing to provide Personal Data may constitute, in some cases, a legitimate and justified reason for not processing your order for the purchase of products sold on the Site or not providing the Site’s services.

Disclosure of further Personal Data to us and YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP other than that required for fulfilling legal or contractual obligations and for properly browsing our services with necessary traffic data is optional and does not have any effect on the use of the Site and of its services or on the purchase of products on the Site. We will inform you at every step whether disclosing your Personal Data to us and YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP is compulsory or optional by marking with an appropriate symbol (*) the information that is compulsory or data needed for the purchase of products on the Site.

**4\. To Whom Your Personal Data Will Be Disclosed?**  
Personal Data will be disclosed to third party companies that provide, on behalf of Bottega Veneta SA, specific services as data Processors or to other recipients of Personal Data collected by us or YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP that autonomously process your Personal Data only for the E-Commerce purposes and, in any case, according to the Governing Law.

Your Personal Data may also be provided to the following companies belonging to Kering Group, with registered offices in EU countries or non EU countries, for their own marketing purposes:

  * <http://www.kering.com/en/brands>

Please contact our [Customer Care](https://www.bottegaveneta.com/clientservice/contact-us/) if you would like to receive a full updated list of Kering Group’s companies.

Notwithstanding the foregoing, Personal Data will not be disclosed to any other third parties or disseminated or transferred without informing our Users of such disclosure/dissemination/transfer, and, in any case, in accordance with the Governing Law.

**5\. Security Measures**  
We have adopted security measures to protect Personal Data against accidental or unlawful destruction, accidental loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access, and against all other reasons for data processing that do not comply with our Privacy Policy. For the best possible protection of your Personal Data outside the limits of our or YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP’s control and management of the same, it is advisable that your computer be provided with software devices that protect network data transmission/receipt (such as updated antivirus systems) and that your Internet service provider take appropriate measures for the security of network data transmission (such as, for example, firewalls and anti-spam filtering).

While we take all reasonable steps to protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure, we cannot make any guarantees in this regard. In particular, online payments are secured through the https protocol in order for your data to be encrypted during their transmission to the payment processor. In some other cases, transmitting data over the Internet is not assured to be secure from access by unintended recipients. We will not be responsible for any breach of security unless this is due to our negligence.

**6\. Cookies**  
This website uses cookies according to our Cookie Policy. This Cookie Policy is available to users on each page of the website linked to this Privacy Policy and on each information banner regarding cookies.

The acceptance of automatic data collection procedures and the use of cookies are necessary for using the Site and its services, including the purchase of products. If you have started the procedure of blocking or deleting cookies, we or YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP cannot ensure that all web pages of the Site will be displayed or that certain services will be supplied such as, for example, storage or display on the web pages of products you chose when you were finalizing the online purchase processes.

The Site uses automatic systems of browsing data collection, such as cookies. A cookie is a file stored on the hard disk of the terminal of an Internet user; it does not contain intelligible information but it allows linking between a terminal and other information about User’s experience on the website and his/her preferences expressed while choosing services and purchasing products offered by the website. For Cookies disseminated by our servers, no one else may gain access to the information contained therein. These information and data are gathered directly and automatically by the Site. The information collected by cookies will be processed in order to optimize the services of the Site. We and YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP have provided cookies in connection to functions such as selecting the country, the language, the location, browsing the catalogue, purchasing products online and in general in connection with the provision of services reserved to registered customers. As you know, each Internet browser allows the blocking or the deletion of cookies. Your Internet browser contains instructions on these procedures. Please access the information on your internet browser if you wish to delete cookies.

**7\. Compulsory processing**  
We wish to inform you that us or YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP may process your Personal Data also without your consent in certain circumstances provided by laws.

**8\. Your Right to Access Personal Data and Further Rights**  
You are entitled to obtain, at any time, confirmation from us or YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP as to whether or not data relating to you is being processed, whether the data is not yet registered, and the communication in intelligible form of the data undergoing processing. Moreover, you are entitled to receive from us or YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP information on the source of your Personal Data; the purposes and way of processing your Personal Data; the logic involved in any electronic data processing; details of the Controller and of the data processors; the names of the entities and categories of entities to whom your Personal Data may be disclosed or who may access your Personal Data, for example, as a Controller or a party so appointed. You can easily find part of the above information in our Privacy Policy. For further information, contact our [Customer Care](https://www.bottegaveneta.com/clientservice/contact-us/).

You are entitled to obtain at any time from us or YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP:

a. the updating or adjustment of your personal data;

b. the deletion, the transformation into an anonymous form or blocking of your personal data (unlawfully processed), including data which does not need to be stored for the purposes for which it was collected and subsequently processed;

c. the confirmation that the operations under letters a) and b) have been reported (together with the contents of the same) to whom the data was disclosed or disseminated, except when it becomes impossible or if the means used are clearly disproportionate to the protection of users’ rights’.

You are entitled to object, in whole or in part:

a. for legitimate reasons, to the processing of your personal data, even if it is related to the purposes for which it was collected;

b. to the processing of your personal data for advertising or direct marketing purposes or in order to carry out marketing research or commercial communications.

The right to object, in whole or in part, to the processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes through automated means of contact extends also to the processing of the data through non-automated means. You may always express your preference to receive marketing communications only with traditional means of contract by contacting us and/or YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP as explained below.

You may freely exercise your rights at any time, provided that you do so in compliance with the Governing Law, by sending your request to us and/or YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP through our [Customer Care](https://www.bottegaveneta.com/clientservice/contact-us/) or by writing to us at our respective address mentioned in introduction to this Privacy Policy. We or YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP will reply to you as necessary.

**9\. Consent**  
Each time your consent is required, Bottega Veneta SA will inform you in advance and will give you the option to either provide or refuse your consent for the use of your Personal Data, including your email address, for the above purposes, by ticking the appropriate boxes.

We wish to inform you that us and/or YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP may process your Personal Data also without your consent in certain circumstances, such as when such processing is necessary for performing a legal obligation to which us and/or YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP are subject or when such processing is necessary for performing obligations undertaken in contracts with the users.

To the extent of the Governing Law and subject to your rights, Your personal data may be processed by Bottega Veneta SA for sending you advertising or offers for Marketing Purposes about products and services unless you object to it at any time, either when Your Personal Data has been collected or at any time, notably when receiving any offer from Us.

In any case, we wish to inform you that YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP and Bottega Veneta SA guarantee that its users may exercise, at any time and without having to state their reasoning, their right not to receive future communications connected to particular services upon request.

**10\. Links to Other Web Sites**  
We or YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP do not control or monitor such web sites or their web content. We or YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP shall not be held liable for the web content of such sites and for the rules adopted by them in terms of your privacy and the processing of your Personal Data while you are visiting those web sites. Please, pay attention when you connect to these web sites through the links provided on our web site and read their terms and conditions of use and their privacy policy carefully. Our Privacy Policy does not apply to third party web sites and we or YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP are by no means liable for the privacy policy adopted by those web sites. The Site provides links to other web sites exclusively to help its Users in their searches and net-surfing activities and to allow links to other web sites on the internet. When we or YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP provide links to other web sites, we do not recommend the use of these web sites and do not provide any guarantees regarding their web content or the services and products supplied and sold by these web sites to Internet Users.

**11\. Contacts**  
If you wish to receive further information on how we and/or YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP process your Personal Data, please contact our [Customer Care](https://www.bottegaveneta.com/clientservice/contact-us/).

**12\. Governing Law**  
This Privacy Policy is governed by the Italian Data Protection Code, set forth by Legislative Decree of June 30, 2003, no. 196 (hereinafter, the “ **Governing Law** ”) for the processing of Personal Data carried out by YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP as a Controller for online selling operations management, as well as for the other processing of Personal Data carried out by Bottega Veneta SA as Controller through appointment of ContactLab S.r.l. as a data Processor for Marketing Purposes (Section 5, paragraph 2, of the Italian Data Protection Code).

Bottega Veneta SA has appointed B.V. Italia S.r.l., located at Località Conti Maltraverso no. 1, Montebello Vicentino (VI), Italy, as national representative in Italy with reference to the collection of certain data.

**13\. Amendments and Updating of this Privacy Policy**  
Bottega Veneta SA and YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP may amend or simply update all or part of this Privacy Policy, including when amendments are made to legal provisions or regulations which govern data protection and protect your rights. The amendments and the updating of the Privacy Policy shall be applicable as soon as they are published on the Site in this section. Therefore, you are requested to regularly access this section in order to check the publication of the most recent and updated Privacy Policy.

**14\. Privacy Policy for Residents in the United States for Information Collected whilst Making Purchases in Bottega Veneta, Inc.’s Shops**  
Bottega Veneta, Inc., located at, 50 Hartz Way, NJ 07094 Secaucus – New Jersey, as data controller with respect to your personal data, may process, also through electronic means, your personal data voluntarily provided or otherwise gathered for the purposes of contractual relationship management, including after-sale services, and for the purpose of sending you communications including phone, sms, email, and for market research.  
Moreover, your personal data will be: communicated to Bottega Veneta SA, which is based in Switzerland (registered office in Via Industria 19, 6814 Cadempino), acting as data controller, for synchronizing and consolidating your personal data for profiling purposes by collecting and processing your personal data obtained from you during your purchases in other shops of the Bottega Veneta Group and for sending marketing and promotional communications, including for market research and analysis, and that may process your data whether through electronic means or otherwise; subsequently communicated by Bottega Veneta SA, subject to applicable Swiss law, to Bottega Veneta, Inc., and to other companies of the Bottega Veneta Group worldwide, acting as autonomous data controllers for purposes relating to sending of marketing and promotional communications (a full list of the companies of the Bottega Veneta Group to whom data will be communicated is available at the following web address: bottegaveneta.com), or communicated by Bottega Veneta SA to third parties for performance of services functional to the above-mentioned purposes.  
Providing your personal data is optional. However, without your personal data, we will be unable to carry out above activities and services. You are entitled, at any time, to request access, update, correct, integrate, delete your personal data, withdraw consent you have provided in relation to the processing of your personal data (including for phone, sms, email communications), and ask for information about the policies, practices and complaint processes implemented by Bottega Veneta, Inc., in relation to processing of the data and to obtain the updated list of data processors, of the companies of the Bottega Veneta Group and third parties to whom your personal data are communicated as well as you may revoke your consent to processing and use of your personal data at any time and such revocation will apply simultaneously to all companies of the Bottega Veneta Group by contacting our Customer Service at +8008456790 or writing in the appropriate [Customer Care contact form](https://www.bottegaveneta.com/clientservice/contact-us/) and selecting ‘Privacy’ as the subject.

**15\. Privacy notice for the use of rfid tags on Bottega Veneta products**  
In order to insure the authenticity of our products, and to provide you with enhanced customer service, Bottega Veneta now utilizes RFID tags containing information relating to the manufacture and purchase of the product. This information is registered on the tag during the production process in order to identify each piece as genuine and unique.

In the event of a quality defect or needed repair, the product can be authenticated at any Bottega Veneta store and all product information necessary to provide you with enhanced repair and post-sale service can be retrieved.

No personal information is stored on the product tags. Bottega Veneta does not associate the information contained in the product tag with other information either available or gathered from third parties to identify you. The only use of these tags is to provide authentication and improved post-sale service.

Furthermore, all information is processed through tags (electronically) in line with the Privacy Code, incorporating security measures to avoid possible misuse of tag\s.

If you wish to refuse this service, you may ask our store personnel to deactivate the tag at any time. You may decide to provide or not the data necessary to enhance Bottega Veneta post-sale services; if you refuse there will be no consequence. Our personnel in charge of processing and the data Processor, if appointed, will access data; upon request we will provide you the updated list of Processors and data recipients. We may communicate data to other companies of the Kering Group and third parties service providers to perform activities necessary to our post-sale services, and as required by laws or regulations. You have all rights provided by the art. 7 of Italian Privacy Code end you can contact the Data Owner in the section “contact” of our site.
